Satwick Ghosh

Systems Engineer

Satwick Ghosh

satgsxs2010@gmail.com



I am a Systems Engineer with over 3 years of experience in the BFSI domain, specialising in Release Manager and software development. I aim to leverage my organisational and communication skills in a challenging role, focusing on business development and technical delivery responsibilities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES | SYSTEMS ENGINEER

May 2021 - Present | Kolkata, India

- → Tasked with overseeing all kinds of enhancements and modifications carried out on a Claims Management/Processing application, managing updates to improve functionality and user experience, and ensuring changes met compliance and performance standards.
- → Experience as a Release Manager, planning and managing scheduled and ad hoc release cycles, coordinating with cross-functional stakeholders, ensuring timely and high-quality releases, and mitigating risks.
- → Acquired proficiency in Automation Testing, specializing in various application domains utilizing UFT. Managed automation suites, ensuring the maintenance and execution of test cases as needed.
- → Streamlined Automation Regression and Performance Testing, leading to a 15% increase in testing efficiency for monthly releases across 9 delivery teams.
- → Orchestrated the planning and development of new underwriting features for US based insurance clients, enhancing risk assessment accuracy.
- → Analyzed and optimized existing codebase according to client specifications resulting in a increase in system performance and reducing bug-related customer complaints.

CHOLA PEOPLE AND MARKETING SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED

| BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER - SME BUSINESS
June 2019 - April 2021 | Siliguri, India

- → Served as a Business Development Manager in the SME (non-motor) insurance vertical, successfully onboarding major property insurance broking houses and top SME-focused agents to drive business growth.
- → Supervised and coordinated SME business operations across 13 locations in North Bengal.
- → Facilitated comprehensive training programs for over 150 agents, brokers and branch managers, resulting in a 30% rise in overall sales performance.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND POSITIONS

- → Received client recognition for efficiently collaborating with multiple teams to deploy a major new functionality. Analyzed risk and performance to ensure successful implementation as a Release Manager.
- → Received praise from the client for promptly and effectively resolving an issue that arose after the software deployment.
- → Coordinator to NSS(National Service Scheme), organised multiple events helping social causes.

EDUCATION

KALINGA INSTITUTE OF INDUSTRIAL TECHNOLOGY (KIIT-DU)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY 2015 - 2019 | Bhubaneswar, India School of Mechanical Engineering CGPA: 7.84 / 10.0

DAV MODEL SCHOOL

HIGHER SECONDARY | CBSE 2013-2015 | Durgapur, India Percentage: 84.33

ST. XAVIER'S SCHOOL

SECONDARY | ICSE 2002-2013 | Durgapur, India Percentage: 85.33

IT SKILLS

C • ASP.NET MySQL • SSIS Automated Testing • UFT Microsoft Suite • Google Suite ServiceNow • Jira Bitbucket • TFS • GitLab Agile Framework - Scrum

LANGUAGES

- English Proficiency level 5
- Bengali Proficiency level 5
- Hindi Proficiency level 4